<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An additional act for stating and determining the accompts of the officers and soldiers of the army in Ireland</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1653</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A74470</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E1062_10</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R209400</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99868281</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99868281</idno>
            <idno type="VID">169148</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A74470)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 169148)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 158:E1062[10])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An additional act for stating and determining the accompts of the officers and soldiers of the army in Ireland</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>33-35 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Iohn Field, printer to the Parliament of England,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1653]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>On F1: the last word of first line of text: 'Par-'; first word of line below initial: 'the'; the last word of last full line of text: 'the'.</note>
                  <note>Also issued as part of a through-paged folio set.</note>
                  <note>Text in black letter.</note>
                  <note>Order to print dated: 8 August, 1653.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Army --  Pay, allowances, etc. --  Law and legislation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="Act_of_Parliament">
            <pb facs="tcp:169148:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 14 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:169148:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 15 -->
            <pb n="33" facs="tcp:169148:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 15 -->
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>seal of the Commonwealth</figDesc>
               </figure>An Additional Act FOR Stating and Determining the Accompts of the Officers and Soldiers of the Army in <hi>IRELAND.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas by an Act of the laſt Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, bearing date the Fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth day of <hi>Auguſt, 1652.</hi> (Enti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuled, <hi>An Act for ſtating and determin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Accompts of ſuch Officers and Soldiers as are or have been imployed in the Service of this Commonwealth in Ireland</hi>) Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion is made for ſtating the Arrears of the ſaid Officers and Soldiers for the time then paſt, or for Compounding for the ſame, according to the Rules and Directions therein given: But for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>aſmuch as a further Arrear is incurred ſince the
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:169148:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 16 -->paſsing of the ſaid Act, Be it Declared and Enacted by this preſent Parliament, and it is hereby Declared and Enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity thereof, That <hi>Nicholas Domvile</hi> Gent. <hi>Robert Jeofferies</hi> Gent. and other the Commiſſioners in the ſaid Act named, or any two of them, ſhall be and are hereby impowred to ſtate, certifie, and give Debentures for all or any the Arrears of the ſaid Officers or Soldiers, which have or ſhall grow due for their ſervice in <hi>Ireland,</hi> until the Three and twentieth day of <hi>October</hi> next coming, in this preſent year One thouſand ſix hundred fifty three; and if any of the ſaid Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers or Soldiers are or ſhall be disbanded be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore that time, The ſaid Commiſsioners are re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired and authorized to ſtate their Accompts, unto the time of their Diſbanding, and to give forth to them Debentures accordingly: And in caſe of the deceaſe of any Officer or Soldier before the ſaid Three and twentieth of <hi>October,</hi> or the time appointed for their Disbanding, or of their leaving the Army or Service by Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſe, or of being Caſhiered, and not Sentenced by the Court Martial to loſe his or their Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rears; The ſaid Commiſsioners are hereby authorized to ſtate his or their Accompts to the time of ſuch deceaſe, departing or caſhiering, and to give forth Debentures to them, their Executors or Adminiſtrators accordingly; or in caſe they or any of them ſhall chooſe to proceed by the way of Compoſition for their Arrears, The ſaid Commiſsioners are therein to allow them for the Arrears incurred, ſince the date of the ſaid former Act. And be it further Enact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and Declared by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Commiſsioners be and are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Impowred to Compound for Arrears ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:169148:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 16 -->to the ſaid Act, with the lawful At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torny or Attornies of any Officer or Soldier, who by reaſon of diſtance of place, or becauſe of attendance on their duty, or for other cauſes cannot perſonally repair to the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners; as alſo with the Attorny or Attornies of the Executor or Adminiſtrator of any Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer or Soldier deceaſed; and ſuch Compoſitions with them made, ſhall be as good and effectual to all intents and purpoſes, as if it had been made with the perſon or perſons immediatly to whom the ſaid Arrears were due.</p>
            <p>Provided always, That this Act, or any thing therein contained, ſhall not extend to the giving to any Officer or Soldier, who are ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judged by the ſaid former Act to have forfeited their Arrears, any benefit or advantage of their Arrears ſo forfeited; nor to the taking a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way any Limitations or Reſtrictions provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded by the ſaid former Act, concerning the Cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificates or Vouchers to be produced to evidence any Arrears, nor to the making void any pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty laid by the ſaid former Act on any that ſhall produce falſe Certificates or Vouchers, thereby fraudulently to demand Arrears.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="license">
            <head>
               <date>
                  <hi>Monday the</hi> 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 
                  <hi>of</hi> Auguſt, 1653.</date>
            </head>
            <p>ORdered by the Parliament, That this Act be forthwith printed and publiſhed.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Hen: Scobell, Clerk of the Parliament.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed by <hi>Iohn Field,</hi> Printer to the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament of <hi>England.</hi> 1653.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
